Guide to the Dawn Langley Simmons Papers, 1848-2014 RL.01190
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Audiovisual Materials Series, circa 1910-1980s and undated, bulk 1979-1980s, 4 boxes
  Consists of audio and video magnetic tape recordings and photographs. The recordings include BBC productions on Dawn Simmons and Margaret Rutherford, spoken renditions of Simmons' work, and a tape of Simmons' wedding. The photographs cover a wide variety of subjects including Isabel and Martha Whitney's family, Dawn Simmons' family, relatives, friends. Other photographs documenting Simmons' life are included in the Writings Series with material collected for publication in Dawn: A Charleston Legend, and in the Scrapbooks Series. The material is in rough chronological order.
  - Audio and Video Materials Subseries, 1969-1980s and undated, 2 boxes
    Conditions Governing Access note
    [Originals CLOSED to use. Use copies for most items are available in Box 67. Otherwise, Technical Services staff must arrange for use copies to be made before contents can be accessed. Please contact Research Services staff before coming to use this collection.]
    - 1969, Recording made by Pauline Ticehurst at Dawn Langley Simmons' wedding, (audio 1/4" tape, 5" reel) (Box 66)
      [Use copy on audiocassette tape and CD-R available in Box 67.]
    - 1979 Apr. 3, Voice recording of Margaret Rutherford - Talk on "Women's Hour," B.B.C. (audio cassette tape) (Box 66)
      [Use copy on audiocassette tape available in Box 67.]
    - 1980, Rumer Godden, "Memories of Margaret Rutherford" (audio cassette tape) (Box 66)
      [Use copy not available; contact Research Services staff to arrange access before coming to use this collection.]
    - 1985 Sept. 11, Whicker's World: "British Women in America," Program No. 50 NBSE 4084, B.B.C., (Umatic video cassette tape) (Box 66)
      [Undated master preservation copy on BetacamSP available in Box 67. Use copy not available; contact Research Services staff to arrange access before coming to use this collection. ]
      - Umatic video cassette (Box 66, Video-cassette RL01190-UM-0001)
      - Betacam video cassette (Box 67, Video-cassette RL01190-Bcam-0001)
        - Digital preservation file (Digital-materials RL01190-SET-0001, Video-file RL01190-Bcam-0001.mov)
    - Undated, The Pierre Berton Show: "The Boy Who Should Have Been a Girl," Program No. 1647 (audio 1/4" tape, 7" reel) (Box 66)
    - Undated, The Pierre Berton Show: "Terrors of a Southern Mixed Marriage," Program No. 1648 (audio 1/4" tape, 7" reel) (Box 66)
    - USE COPIES (Box 67)
      [See listings above for titles and use copy information.]
  - Photographic Materials Subseries, circa 1910-1980s and undated, 2 boxes
    - Photographic materials, circa 1910-1980s and undated (Box 68)
    - Large format photographic materials, undated (Box 31)
- Oversize Materials, 2 folders
  - Printed Materials Series, 1958-1994 and undated
    - Cover proofs for Dawn, A Charleston Legend, circa 1994 (Oversize-folder 1)
    - Bette Davis movie poster; oversize newspaper clippings; magazine article about Simmons marriage; Look magazine issue; award and diploma; architect plans for door frame; publicity poster for The People with Simmons as "famous author" in wedding dress, entitled "My New Life as a Woman." (Oversize-folder 2)